[Music]
hello everyone and welcome to this
business Central lunch event session on
the customer managed encryption key um
this is a new functionality that uh
delivers on a need that we frequently
hear from customers with very Advanced
uh data governance uh and privacy
standards and it's the ability to
encrypt your business Central
environment database using your own
encryption key in your own aure key fold
let's start with a demo of how to set
this up right away um and to start we
need to set up a key vault in the Azure
portal so we go to create a resource
choose to create a new key
Vault and fill in the basic properties
on this page so for our purposes what's
important is that we pick um a name for
the key Vault I'll go with cmk ble for
now we pick a region which must match
the region of your business C
environment so in this case I'm setting
it up for Canadian business Central
environment so I'm picking the Canada
central region and what's also important
here is in the bottom the perge
protection this must be enabled on key
vaults that contain a key um that will
be used to encrypt your environment
database for now I'll skip all the other
optional settings um you can use them
but they're not required for cmk I'll
just review and then create this key
volt now that the deployment is complete
let's go straight to the resource the
KEYT that was just created in Canada
Central and navigate to the keys to
create the key that will in the end be
used to encrypt my envir IR database to
that I navigate to Keys here then go to
generate
slimport and uh really only give it a
name so all the other default values
here uh are sufficient for cmk you can
choose to use them but you don't have to
um create that key I can see the key is
here
now now that I've created my key uh it's
time to make sure that there's a
resource that connects the key to my
Power Platform environment which then
connects to my business en environment
and to do that I first need to make sure
that the Power Platform resource
provider is enabled for my Azure
subscription so from the subscription
page for my ble subscription here I
navigate to Resource
providers and then I searched for the
name microsoft. powerplatform you can
see here for this subscription it's
already enabled but by default it would
not be in that case just s the box and
make sure you register it here next it's
time to create another resource there
will be a custom deployment that
connects the key to your Power Platform
environment
and for that I actually create a new
resource uh as a template deployment
using a custom template so go here click
create and I go straight into the
template editor when I go into the
template editor there's this default
mtjs but there's a sample of what you
need to create the Enterprise policy
resource on the Power Platform
documentation so you can copy paste from
there and replace a few
parameters um what's important here is
that you give it a description name I'll
go with cmk ble policy the Loc
must match the location of your Power
Platform and your business Central
environment in my case
Canada um and the ID of the key here
most match the ID of the key resource
that contains the key with which you
want to encrypt your database so in my
case this is the key that I just
created um and the key name here is the
name of the key that I just
created now that all looks good I'll go
save I deploy it in Canada Central of
course um I'll go to review and create
all looks good it post devel valtion and
I create this
resource now that the deployment has
completed I navigate straight to the
resource and I can see that this
Enterprise policy has indeed been
created um the next step now is to make
sure that the user that will end up
setting up cmk in the Power Platform
admin Center later on has access to this
resource so that they can find it from
the Power Platform admin Center to do
that I go into Access Control here I go
into add Ro assignment and I make sure
that I select reader
now that I have selected the the reader
role I add a new member in this case
I'll use my own admin user but ideally
you would use a different user between
the setup in Azure and Power Platform so
here you would select the user that
finishes the setup in the Power Platform
admin Center
later select my admin user
review the row assignments and then
confirm next I navigate back to the key
that I created earlier um cuz in this
key I now need to make sure that the
Enterprise policy resource I've just
created has access to read the keys in
the KEYT to do that I go to access
control here I add a ro
assignment I add a ro assignment and I
look for the key crypto service
encryption user role select that role
and then select the managed identity
member to assign it
to um for manage identity type here you
select the Power Platform type and then
you'll find
the resource that you've just created of
the uh Enterprise
policy I select this manage identity
review that it all looks good so I have
my Enterprise policy resource here um
given it key crypto service encryption
user role in the key that contains the
key that I want to encrypt my
environment with I review and assign and
then confirm and with assigning this raw
assignment to the Enterprise policy I've
just created that concludes the setup
required in the Azure portal and it's
time to move on to the Power Platform
admin
Center and you can see here I have an
environment that is indeed in region
Canada just like my key and my
Enterprise policy and uh also important
to mention here is that this is a
managed environment so um cmk only works
on managed
environments to continue setting up cmk
on this particular environment I go into
security and I choose data and
privacy and then I choose the customer
manag encryption key and you can see
here that my user indeed has re
permissions to a policy that exist in my
Azure uh subscription so I go on select
this policy edit the
policy and then add an environment to it
so you can see here um out of all the
environments that are in the same region
as that policy there's only one my
production environment in Canada as
selected and then continue review that
this looks good save it then review the
warning here which warns me that this
will start encrypting the database right
away which may take some time to
complete so make sure that you apply
this at a time that the environment can
be down while it's being
encrypted I confirm that that's okay and
I can now see on the cmk ble policy
details here that my production
environment is being
encrypted finally now that I've set this
up for my Power Platform environment
it's time to set it up for my business
Central environment as well um so you
can see here I have a production en
environment that is in Canada uh but
it's not linked to any Power Platform
environment business Central
environments inherit the cmk setting
from their linked by platform
environment so to enable this for my
business Cal environment it's time to
link the environment can see that I'm in
need able to link my business Central
environment to my production Power
Platform environment and that's possible
because this environment is not linked
to anything else it is also in Canada
and it's of the same type so both are
production
environments I confirm that I want to
link and I can immediately see that the
the linking succeeded and the customer
manage encryption key is set so now my
business s for envirment is also
encrypted using my customer managed
encryption key so before you set up cmk
there's a few things that are good to
know first of all as I've just demoed uh
cmk requires a linked Power Platform
environment and this has two
implications first of all if you unlink
your environment after applying cmk your
business and for environment will
automatically revert to a Microsoft
manage encryption key secondly if you
copy or restore your
environment um while it is encrypted
with cmk you create a new environment
that will not by default be encrypted
with the same key so after that copy of
restore operation completes you'd have
to um link it to a new Power Platform
environment and apply cmk to That Power
Platform environment as well and then
finally if you export your environment
um you create a backpack file in a
storage account and that storage account
will be encrypted by default with a
Microsoft manage encryption key but of
course you can choose to um re Crypt
that storage account with your own key
as well secondly the linked environment
must be a managed environment so as I
just showed in the demo the Power
Platform environment for which I set
this up was a managed environment um and
that is required for CK to work to use a
managed environment this comes with some
uh specific licensing requirements
beyond your business Central license so
before you can set up cmk you need to
make sure that you have uh certain
Microsoft 365 and Power Platform
licensing requirements in place finally
in My Demo I used the single user to set
this all up but in the real word is
important to uh separate the duties in
setting this up between different users
you'd use a key administrator for all
the setup I did in AER portal and then a
separate user who's a dynamic 365
administrator or a Power Platform
administrator for all the setup I
completed in the Power Platform admin
Center um that completes this session on
cmk thanks for watching